Guide to the Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union, Local 1-S, Records WAG.012
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II: General and Macy's Herald Square Files, 1939-1997
  - Wages: Pro Rates, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Wages: Pro Rates, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Wages: Wage Freeze Petition, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Wages: Wage Rates, 1939-1940 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Wages: Wage Rates, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Wages: Wage Rates, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Wages: Wage Rates, 1953-1954 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Wages: Wage Rates, 1956-1957 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Wages: Wage Rates, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Wages: Wage Rates, 1961 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Wages: Wage Rates, 1962-1963 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Wages: Wage Rates, 1962-1963 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Wages: Wage Rates, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Wages: Wage Rates, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Photographs, 1959-1979 (Box Shared Tamiment 018, Folder 16)
- Series III: Other Shop Files, 1944-1972
  - Alexander's Department Stores: Organizing, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - B. Altman and Company: Organizing, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Gertz: Organizing, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Lord & Taylor: Organizing, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Ludwig Baumann and Company: Arbitration, 1950-1951 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Ludwig Baumann and Company: Organizing, 1949-1950 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Macy's Flatbush: Organizing, 1948-1950 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Macy's Jamaica: Organizing, 1947-1948 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Macy's Paramus (Bamberger's): Organizing, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Macy's Parkchester: Agreements, 1944-1949 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Macy's Parkchester: National War Labor Board Agreement, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Macy's Queens: Circulars, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Macy's Roosevelt Field: Arbitration, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Macy's Roosevelt Field: Circulars, 1956-1959 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Macy's Roosevelt Field: Company Memos and Circulars, 1958-1959 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Macy's Roosevelt Field: Departments, undated (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Macy's Roosevelt Field: "Local 1-S Roosevelt Field News" (shop paper), 1959 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Macy's Roosevelt Field: Organizing, 1956-1959, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Macy's White Plains: Circulars, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Suburban Foods: Agreements, 1961-1968 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Suburban Foods: Arbitration, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Suburban Foods: Correspondence, 1961-1967 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Suburban Foods: Grievances, 1962-1972 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Suburban Foods: Ground Rules Committee, 1966-1967 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Suburban Foods: Health Plan, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Suburban Foods: Meeting Notes and Attendance, 1962, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Suburban Foods: Negotiations, 1961-1968 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Suburban Foods: Pension, 1965-1970 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Suburban Foods: Salespeople, 1960-1969 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Ohrbach's: Organizing, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Ohrbach's: Organizing Circulars, 1962-1964 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Pomeroy's: Organizing, 1955 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Series IV: Sam Kovenetsky Files, 1943-1979
  - American Cancer Society, 1973-1975 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Biographical Information, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Conference Notes, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1965-1979 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: Internal, 1965, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence: Letters of Recommendation, 1974-1977 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence: Macy's, 1940-1949 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence: Macy's, 1970-1974 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence: Other Unions, 1943, 1951-1977 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence: Personal, 1959-1977 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Fortuna Lodge No. 318, International Order of Odd Fellows, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Greater New York Fund, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Greater New York Fund, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Greater New York Fund, 1973-1974 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Greater New York Fund, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Greater New York Fund, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Group Health Insurance, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Group Health Insurance, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Group Health Insurance, 1975-1976 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Group Health Insurance: Minutes, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Group Health Insurance: Minutes, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Group Health Insurance: Minutes, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Group Health Insurance: Minutes, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Industrial Relations Research Association, New York Chapter, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Israel Histadrut Associates, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Japan Trip (sponsored by Japan Federation of Commercial Workers Unions), 1970 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Jewish National Fund, undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Labor Committee to Back Carter Campaign, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Labor for Carey Committee, 1974-1975 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - March on Washington, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Meeting Notes, 1968-1975 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Poems, undated (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Proclamation on Crossing the International Date Line, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Speeches, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Speeches, 1954-1958 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Sales Tax Increase: Clippings and Statement, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Teamsters Lodge #2201, B'nai B'rith, 1966-1975 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Temple Israel of Putnam Valley, 1976-1977 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - United Hebrew Trades, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Workmen's Circle Home and Infirmary for the Aged, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 28)
- Series V: Legal Counsel Files, 1947-1974
  - 1-S Corporation, 1960-1965 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - 1-S Limited Profit Housing Corporation, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Agreements: Saturday Onlies, 1953-1956 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Arbitrations, 1947-1964 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Arbitrations: Cole, David, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Arbitrations: Elimination of Children's Shoe-fitter Classification, 1969-1970 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Arbitrations: Farley, Charles, Jul 1957 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Arbitrations: L. Bamberger and Company, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Arbitrations: Macy's Huntington, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Arbitrations: Macy's Queens, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Arbitrations: Macy's Roosevelt Field Auto Center, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Arbitrations: Ohrbach's, 1962-1964 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Arbitrations: Picketing, 1971-1972, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Arbitrations: Rawdin, Eugene, Feb 1958 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Arbitrations: Smooke, Irving, Sep 1966 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Arbitrations: Stein, Emanuel, 1952-1953 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Arbitrations: Stock Clerk Classification, Dec 1958 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Arbitrations: Stock Counts by Vendors, Mar 1965 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Arbitrations: Vanderbilt Automotive Centers, 1967-1973 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Arbitrations: Violation of Wage Schedule Provisions, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Arbitrations: Wage Schedule in Merged Shoe Department, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Arbitrations: Wrapping "Sent" Packages, Oct 1957 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - City Island Property Purchase, 1963-1967 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Constitution and By-Laws Changes, 1953, 1959-1970 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, 1962-1969 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1974 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Elections Challenge (Joseph Pascarella and Leo Gomez), 1972 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Equal Pay for Women, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Negotiations, 1953-1954 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Negotiations, 1956-1965 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Negotiations, 1967-1968 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Negotiations, 1970-1972 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Negotiations: Macy's Queens, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Office Lease, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Pay Board, 1972-1973 (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Pension Plan, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - Proposed Merger (Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Workers Union with Distributive, Processing and Office Workers Union and United Department Store Workers of America), 1953-1955 (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - United Department Store Workers of America, CIO, 1952-1969 (Box 13, Folder 38)
- Series VI: Archived Websites, March 2009-ongoing; 3 websites in 3 archived websites.
  Scope and Content Note
  Local 1-S is a local branch of the Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union/UFCW (RWDSU), which represents employees at the Macy's department store in Herald Square, Manhattan and the workers in the Queens and Parkchester stores. The union works to protect Macy's employees' right to the fair wages and benefits that allow them to support themselves and their families. Crawling of the website began in 2009 and contained information on officers and stewards, scholarships and other benefits, health and safety in retail, rights on the job, grievance procedures, vacation policy, contracts, political action and voter registration, newsletters dating back to 2002, photo galleries, and other news. In 2011, the website focused on contract negotiations with Macy's and Macy's furniture store unionization efforts in Elmhurt, Queens. There was a gap of crawling between 2015-2018. Crawling at a new URL began in 2018. The new website contained mostly news related to the 2016 contract negotiations. In 2020, the website updated with information related to the COVID-19 pandemic, specifically the Macy's temporary store closure in March 2020, furloughs, COVID-19 safety, and reopening in June 2020. It redirected to new URLs in 2021 and 2023. The current website contains information on the 2023 contract negotiations, biographies of the union leadership, and information on worker rights.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
  Accruals
  New site crawls accrued semiannually.
  Appraisal
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of https://rwdsulocal1s.org/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.